Guide to the Lynn Wyatt scrapbooks and memorabilia, 1931-2012 MS 550
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Lynn Wyatt Scrapbooks and Memorabilia
1931-2012
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Wyatt, Lynn Sakowitz
MS 550
26 Linear Feet (26 boxes)
5.24 Gigabytes MS0550aip_001
These scrapbooks contain photographs, correspondence, invitations, event programs, news clippings, and memorabilia collected by Lynn Wyatt, documenting her work with charitable and fine arts organizations, leadership as a Houston socialite and best-dressed icon, and international travels.
Biographical Sketch
Lynn Sakowitz Wyatt, born July 16, 1935, is a prominent Houston-based international socialite, arts patron, and philanthropist. Lynn Wyatt is a third-generation Texan, daughter of the late Bernard Sakowitz and Ann Baum, and sister of Texas high fashion retailer Robert Sakowitz. She married oil and gas executive Oscar Wyatt in 1963 and moved into Allington, a Houston mansion in the River Oaks neighborhood that became known as the "Wyatt Hyatt" for the frequency of visits by royal notables and entertainment icons, such as long-time friend Princess Grace of Monaco, Joan Collins, Elton John and Mick Jagger. In addition to foreign nobility and celebrities, she had also cultivated friendships with several couturiers and was inducted into the International Best Dressed List Hall of Fame in 1977. Her classic style and Southern flair has led to her appearance on magazines covers and amongst the pages of American and Paris Vogue, Town & Country, Vanity Fair, and Harper's Bazaar. In 2000, she was recognized as "Socialite of the Century" by Texas Monthly magazine. She has made great contributions to France, was admitted to the Order of Arts and Letters for significant cultural enrichment, and opened the summer season for over three decades with a lavish birthday party in Monte Carlo on the Cote d'Azur.
She has an extensive record of awards and honors for her lifelong commitment to philanthropy and leadership in the upper echelons of Houston society and was commissioned as an Ambassador of Goodwill for the state of Texas in 1980. Many of her efforts in fundraising and chairing events have concentrated on local fine arts, including the Houston Grand Opera, MFA, Houston Ballet, and Alley Theatre. She recently accepted the first-ever Performing Arts Advocate Award for her contributions to the performing arts in Houston. She was invited by Prince Rainier of Monaco to be a Founding Trustee of the Princess Grace Foundation U.S.A., on which Board she continues to serve, raising and distributing funds to assist emerging talent in theater, dance, and film. Internationally, she has chaired festivities benefitting the Red Cross and the American Hospital of Paris. Her interest in disease prevention and health has led to her charitable participation on the inaugural board of the Medical Prevention and Research Institute in Houston. She has also been recognized for her contributions to women's achievements, including her appointment to the Board of the U.S. Naval Academy by President Reagan as one of the first woman advisors where she served for eight years.
Scope and Contents
These scrapbooks contain photographs, correspondence, invitations, event programs, news clippings, and memorabilia collected by Lynn Wyatt, documenting her work with charitable and fine arts organizations, leadership as a Houston socialite and best-dressed icon, and international travels. There is some material concerning her husband, Oscar Wyatt, and his role in the oil and natural gas industry, and one scrapbook devoted to Princess Caroline, daughter of Lynn Wyatt's close friends the late Prince Rainier III of Monaco and Princess Grace.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was donated by Lynn Wyatt on March 16, 2010.
Index Terms
Subjects
Business; Women's clothing; Philanthropists; Arts and society; Philanthropy and society; Women
Document Types
corrrespondence; clippings (information artifacts); photographs; memorabilia
Places
Art
Subjects (Persons)
Wyatt, Lynn Sakowitz; Caroline, Princess of Hanover; Wyatt, Oscar
- Series I: Scrapbooks, 1978-1998; 106641
  - Photographs, 1978, 106666 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1978, 106667 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1978, 106668 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1978, 106669 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1978, 106670 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Travel postcards, 1978, 106671 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 1979, 107899 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979, 107900 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1979, 107901 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1979, 107902 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1979, 107903 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1980, 107904 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1980, 107905 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1980, 107906 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1980, 107907 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1980, 107908 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Award certificate, 1980, 107909 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Caricatures, 1980, 107910 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 1981, 107911 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1981, 107912 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1981, 107913 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1981, 107914 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1981, 107915 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1982, 107916 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1982, 107917 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1982, 107918 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1982, 107919 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1982 (Folder 1 of 2), 107920 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - News clippings, 1982 (Folder 2 of 2), 107921 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983, 107922 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1983, 107923 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1983, 107924 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1983, 107925 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1984, 107926 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1984, 107927 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1984, 107928 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1984, 107929 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1985, 107930 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985, 107931 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1985, 107932 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1985, 107933 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1985, 107934 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1986, 107935 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1986, 107936 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1986, 107937 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1986, 107938 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1986, 107939 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1987, 107940 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1987, 107941 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1987, 107942 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1987, 107943 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1988, 107944 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1988, 107945 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1988, 107946 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1988, 107947 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1988, 107948 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1989, 107949 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1989, 107950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1989, 107951 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1989, 107952 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1989, 107953 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1990, 107954 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1990, 107955 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1990, 107956 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1990, 107957 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1991, 107958 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1991, 107959 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1991, 107960 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1991, 107961 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Star of Hope and Trees of Hope Festival, 1991, 107962 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - HGO Events, 1991, 107963 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 1992, 107964 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1992, 107965 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1992, 107966 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1992, 107967 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1992, 107968 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Speech drafts, 1992, 107969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 1993, 107970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1993, 107971 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1993, 107972 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1993, 107973 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1993, 107974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1994, 107975 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1994, 107976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1994, 107977 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1994, 107978 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1994, 107979 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Sheet music for "Lynn" by Jerry Herman, 1994, 107980 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, Summer 1994 (Folder 1of 3), 107981 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, Summer 1994 (Folder 2 of 3), 107982 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, Summer 1994 (Folder 3 of 3), 107983 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of India, Nepal, Vietnam and Angkor Thom, 1987, 107984 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Tibet, 1994, 107985 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Travel itineraries for Tibet, Cambodia, and Vietnam, 1994, 107986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Postcards of Bangkok, 107987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1995, 107988 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1995, 107989 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1995, 107990 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1995, 107991 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1996, 107992 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1996, 107993 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1996, 107994 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Invitations, 1996, 107995 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - News clippings, 1996, 107996 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1997, 107997 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, 1997, 107998 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - News clippings, 1997, 107999 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Marathon reading of selections from Joyce's Ulysses, 1997, 108000 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1998, 108001 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1998, 108002 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Invitations, 1998, 108003 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - News clippings, 1998, 108004 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Gala for Princess Caroline, 1978, 108005 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence re: dinner party for Princess Caroline, 1978, 108006 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Dinner party invitation and guest list, 108007 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - News clippings about Princess Caroline, 1978, 108008 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Magazine articles about Princess Caroline, 1978, 108009 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Scans of color images from this series, in TIF format
- Series II: Non-scrapbook photographs, newsclippings and correspondence, 1931-2012, n.d.; 108010
  - Photographs, undated, 108011 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Fortune magazine, August 1931, 108012 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Baby book for Lynn Sakowitz Wyatt, 1935, 108013 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - San Jacinto High School diploma, 1953, 108014 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Wedding gown, 1954, 108015 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Allington decorating correspondence, finances and photos; 1964-68, 108016 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Newsclippings, 1969-72, 108017 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Certificate of Appreciation from the city of Corpus Christi to Oscar Wyatt, 1972, 108018 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Gala at Birmingham-Southern College; 1974-77, 108019 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - News clippings, 1975-77, 108020 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Trip to China (photos and historical notes), 1979, 108021 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Magazine covers, 1985-86, 108022 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Aida, Egypt, 1987, 108023 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Opus Sacrum Exhibition, Warsaw, 1990, 108024 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - "Design for a Jewelry Box for Mrs. Wyatt", 1993, 108025 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - News clippings, 2010, 108026 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Essay on McCarthyism by Lynn Sakowitz Wyatt, 108027 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - French history, 108028 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Memorabilia, 108029 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 108030 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Religious materials, 108031 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Sakowitz, Bernard, 108032 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 1993, 176056 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 1999, 176044 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 2000, 176045 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 2001, 176046 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 2002, 176047 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 2003, 176048 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 2004, 176049 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 2005, 176050 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 2008-09, 176051 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 2010, 176053 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, 2012, 176054 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - News and Magazine Clippings, n.d., 176052 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - Lynn Wyatt Tribute DVD, 2010; 176055 (Box 25, Folder 35)
- Series III: Videotaped Wyatt interviews and events, 1990-2007, n.d.; 108281
  - Mental Health Gala 1990 - Ima Hogg Award Recipient: Lynn Wyatt (VHS), 108282 (Box 26, Cassette 1)
  - "Beauty and the Beast World Premiere/Interview with Lynn Wyatt" - Channel 11 News Special, KHOU-TV (CBS) Houston: December 3, 1993, 7:00-8:00 pm (VHS), 108283 (Box 26, Cassette 2)
  - Lynn Wyatt Video Tribute, Alley Theatre Spring Ball; May 6, 2000 (VHS), 108284 (Box 26, Cassette 3)
  - Lynn Wyatt "InnerViews" with Ernie Manouse for Great Day Houston: Cadillac 2007 Series, "Hot Town, Cool City"; December 2007 (VHS), 108285 (Box 26, Cassette 4)
  - Lynn Wyatt "InnerViews" with Ernie Manouse for Great Day Houston: Cadillac 2007 Series, "Hot Town, Cool City"; December 2007 (VHS), 108286 (Box 26, Cassette 5)
  - Lynn Wyatt "InnerViews" with Ernie Manouse for Great Day Houston: Cadillac 2007 Series, "Hot Town, Cool City"; December 2007 (VHS), 108287 (Box 26, Cassette 6)
  - Lynn Wyatt "InnerViews" with Ernie Manouse for Great Day Houston: Cadillac 2007 Series, "Hot Town, Cool City"; December 2007 (VHS), 108288 (Box 26, Cassette 7)
  - Lynn Wyatt's Villa Romana Birthday/Dinner Party (not dated) (VHS), 108289 (Box 26, Cassette 8)
  - Lynn Wyatt's Villa Romana Birthday/Dinner Party (not dated) (VHS), 108290 (Box 26, Cassette 9)